[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to part six
您好，欢迎来到第六部分
of lesson one. Here we're going to talk about
第一课这里我们要谈的是
how you can reference external variables
如何引用外部变量
when you're dealing with a Lambda expression and how you can go about using
当您处理Lambda表达式以及如何使用时
variables data from the surrounding scope. If you look at
来自周围范围的变量数据。如果你看
anonymous inner classes there are restrictions on
匿名内部类对
how you can reference variables in the surrounding scope.
如何在周围的范围内引用变量。
Essentially, any variable that you reference
本质上，您引用的任何变量
must be marked as final which means it’s value is set once
必须标记为最终值，这意味着它的值设置一次
and isn't modified. This is because
并且未修改。这是因为
in terms of what an anonymous inner class provides,
就匿名内部类提供的内容而言，
it’s effectively a closure on
实际上是对
a value, not a closure on a variable. Different programming languages take
一个值，而不是变量的闭包。不同的编程语言需要
different approaches
不同的方法
in terms of closures. Java has the idea of closures on values,
在关闭方面。 Java的想法是封闭值，
so do languages like Haskell. Some languages
Haskell等语言也是如此。一些语言
like Scala, for example, allow you to check closures on variables,
例如Scala，允许您检查变量的闭包，
which means you can modify a variable
这意味着您可以修改变量
from the surrounding scope. In terms of
从周围的范围。就......而言
why this is quite important is because, for multi-threaded code,
之所以如此重要，是因为对于多线程代码，
what you actually want to do is avoid modifying state.
您实际上想要做的是避免修改状态。
We talked a little about this earlier in the lesson but
在本课程的前面，我们对此进行了一些讨论，但
the problem can occur is if you use a Lambda expression, if you were able to
可能出现的问题是，如果您使用Lambda表达式，
modify the state
修改状态
of a variable in the surrounding scope it could be that that Lambda expression is being used in
周围范围内的变量可能是Lambda表达式用于
several different threads
几个不同的线程
and you could get race conditions, you could get inconsistent data.
并且您可能会获得比赛条件，可能会获得不一致的数据。
For Lambda expressions, because they can be used wherever
对于Lambda表达式，因为它们可以在任何地方使用
you could have the equivalent anonymous inner class we still have the same restriction.
您可以拥有等效的匿名内部类，但我们仍然有相同的限制。
We still have the idea of closures on values, but what we've done
我们仍然有封闭价值的想法，但是我们已经做了
is to relax the rules a little bit.
是放宽规则。
In terms of accessing a variable in the surrounding scope
在访问范围内的变量方面
it must be effectively final. That means it doesn't have to be marked
它必须有效地是最终的。这意味着不必标记
as final, but it has to behave in exactly the same way
最终，但它的行为方式必须完全相同
as if it was marked final.
好像标记为最终的一样。
I’ve got an example here where I’ve got a method called expire
我在这里有一个示例，其中有一个名为expire的方法
and I’m passing a variable called before
我传递了一个叫做before的变量
into that method. I then want to use that
进入那个方法。然后我想用那个
variable, the value before within my Lambda expression.
变量，即Lambda表达式中的before值。
Here I'm testing whether the last modified date is before that date.
在这里，我正在测试上次修改日期是否早于该日期。
Even though before is not marked as final,
即使之前未标记为最终，
its value is only set once it's not modified in the code
仅在代码中未对其修改的情况下才设置其值
so it behaves exactly the same way as if it was marked final.
因此它的行为与标记为final的行为完全相同。
If I added a final into that definition of the parameter
如果我在参数的定义中添加了final
nothing would change in the way the code worked, so I can use that
代码的工作方式不会改变，所以我可以使用它
in my Lambda expression. We need to understand
在我的Lambda表情中。我们需要了解
what this means in terms
这意味着什么
of a Lambda expression. Now we use this
表达式。现在我们用这个
in Java represent the instance of the object that we’re actually using
用Java表示我们实际使用的对象的实例
at that time. In the case of a Lambda expression
那时候。对于Lambda表达式
remember I've said already that a Lambda expression is not
记得我已经说过Lambda表达式不是
associated with a class and therefore there's no
与班级相关，因此没有
object that a Lambda expression is directly associated with. It’s not like an
Lambda表达式直接与之关联的对象。这不像
anonymous inner class
匿名内部类
where the compiler will create a synthetic class for you
编译器将在其中为您创建综合类
on the run time will then instantiate that class and create an object
然后在运行时实例化该类并创建一个对象
of that which you can then refer to as this
您可以将其称为
within an anonymous inner class. A Lambda expression
在匿名内部类中。 Lambda表达式
doesn't have a class; there is no object
没有课程；没有对象
so this cannot refer to the lambda expression itself.
因此，这不能引用lambda表达式本身。
If you use this in a Lambda expression,
如果您在Lambda表达式中使用它，
what you will be referring to is the object
您将要指的是对象
of the surrounding scope. That's something that is a difference between
周围的范围。那是两者之间的区别
Lambda expressions and anonymous inner classes, and it's something to be
Lambda表达式和匿名内部类，这是需要注意的
aware of.
意识到。
That can have some strange effects.
这可能会产生一些奇怪的影响。
This was some code that I wrote,
这是我写的一些代码，
very much like this, in terms of some real code that I was working on.
就我正在处理的一些实际代码而言，非常像这样。
What I did was I had my method called process,
我所做的是我有一个叫做过程的方法，
got some data from somewhere
从某处得到一些数据
and then I incremented currentValue
然后我增加了currentValue
which is a variable in the surrounding scope, and the compiler didn’t complain,
这是周围范围中的变量，编译器没有抱怨，
it compiled the code quite happily. I ran the code and it worked.
它很高兴地编译了代码。我运行了代码，它起作用了。
I looked at it and I thought, that shouldn’t work
我看着它，我以为那不行
because I’m modifying a variable in the surrounding scope,
因为我正在修改周围范围的变量，
and it's not final and it’s not effectively final
这不是最终的，也不是有效的最终
so why does that work? It took me a little while to track this down, but
那为什么行得通呢？我花了一段时间才找到答案，但是
the compiler in this case does a little trick
在这种情况下，编译器有一些技巧
on your behalf. What it does, is actually inserts
代表你。它所做的实际上是插入
a reference to this and remember that this
对此的参考，请记住，
refers to the object of the surrounding scope,
指周围范围的对象，
in this case the DataProcessor object and
在这种情况下，DataProcessor对象和
this is effectively final. Its value is set once it's not modified.
这实际上是最终的。如果不修改，则设置其值。
We can use the reference to this as an effectively final variable
我们可以使用对此的引用作为有效的最终变量
and then reference currentValue through
然后通过以下方式引用currentValue
this. We don't need to worry about
这个。我们不用担心
modifying currentValue and it being a non final variable.
修改currentValue，它是非最终变量。
Personally, I think this is a little bit dangerous because,
我个人认为这有点危险，因为，
as I said, if you have multi-threaded environment you could end up with a
如我所说，如果您具有多线程环境，则可能会遇到
situation where you getting
你得到的情况
inconsistent data and by the compiler inserting this for you
数据不一致，由编译器为您插入
silently it doesn’t
默默地没有
make it obvious what's actually happening.
弄清楚实际情况。
Like as I said, I had to dig quite deep to find out what was actually happening
就像我说的那样，我必须深入研究才能发现实际发生的情况
here,
这里，
so be aware of this as a potential,
所以要意识到这是一种潜力，
in some ways a potentially useful feature, but also a potentially problematic
在某些方面可能是有用的功能，但也可能有问题
feature
特征
when you’re using multiple threads.
当您使用多个线程时。
To summarize section six you can
总结第六部分，您可以
access variables in the surrounding scope of a Lambda
访问Lambda周围范围内的变量
so long as they are effectively final,
只要他们有效地成为决赛，
meaning that they are final or they behave in exactly the same way
表示它们是最终的，或者它们的行为完全相同
as a final variable. If you use this
作为最终变量。如果你用这个
with a Lambda, it refers to the object
用Lambda表示对象
of the surrounding scope and, as I said, be aware
周围的范围，并且正如我所说，要注意
that in situations like the one I showed you the compiler will insert a
在我向您展示的情况下，编译器将插入一个
reference silently for you to enable you to reference a variable in the
静默引用，使您能够在
surrounding scope
周边范围
without having the problems of it being not
没有问题的不是
effectively final. And that is the end
有效地最终。到此为止
of this section of the lesson.
本节内容。